Guide to the Armstrong, Furst & Tilton records, ca.1927-1955.
Armstrong, Furst & Tilton records, ca.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Armstrong, Furst & Tilton records, ca.1927-1955, 1927-1950 (bulk)
2243
Armstrong, Furst & Tilton, Architects (Chicago, Ill.)
130 items.
Blueprints, drawings, photographs, and printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Material of this firm and its successor, Furst & Tilton (after 1950) of Chicago, Illinois. Many items relate to the Seabury-Western Theological Seminary at Evanston, Illinois; others pertain to churches, mainly in Wisconsin and Illinois; also schools, public buildings, business establishments and residences.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Blueprints, drawings, photographs, pamphlets, and printed material of this firm and its successor, Furst & Tilton (after 1950) of Chicago, Illinois. Many items relate to the Seabury-Western Theological Seminary at Evanston, Illinois; others pertain to churches, mainly in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, and cities in Illinois; also schools, public buildings, business establishments and residences.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Armstrong, Furst & Tilton, Architects (Chicago, Ill.); Furst & Tilton, Architects (Chicago, Ill.); Seabury-Western Theological Seminary.
Subjects:
Architecture--Illinois--Evanston.; Architecture--Illinois--Chicago.; Architecture--Wisconsin--Milwaukee.; Architects.
Form and Genre Terms:
Blueprints.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Western Theological Seminary, Built 1928-1934, Evanston, Illinois.
  - Drawing: Plan of Western Theological Seminary. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Preliminary study of library, Western Theological Seminary., 1927 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Drawing: Library School and Chapel from Sheridan Road, Undated (Map-case Folder 1)
  - Drawing: Preliminary Sketch, Interior of Chapel. (Map-case Folder 1)
  - Drawing: N. & E. Elevations: WT Seminary. (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Blueprint: Dormitory Group: WT Seminary, West and North Elevation. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Blueprint: Dormitory Group: W. & E. Elevation, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Blueprint: Dormitory Group: E. & S. Elevation, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Blueprint: Dormitory Group: Basement Plan, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Blueprint: Dormitory Group: First Floor Plan, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Blueprint: Dormitory Group: Second Floor Plan, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Blueprint: Dormitory Group: Third Floor and Roof, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Blueprint: Dormitory Group: First Floor Plan, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Bronze Memorial, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Preliminary Sketch Plan. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Bronze Memorial Tablet, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Dormitory Group, N. & W. Elevation, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Chapel and Tower, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Church. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: W. & E. Elevation, Dormitory Group, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: S. & E. Elevation, Dormitory Group. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Main Floor Plan, Chapel, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Chapel and Tower, Haven Street. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Dormitory Group, Basement Plan, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Details of Church - Inscription in Tower Wall, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Dormitory Group, First Floor Plan, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Dormitory Group, Second Floor Plan, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Dormitory Group, Third Floor Plan, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Ground Floor Plan, Revised, WTS. (Map-case Folder 1, 3)
  - Drawing: Proposed Inscription on Wall. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Preliminary Elevations, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Haven Street Elevations, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Preliminary Sketch Plan, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Preliminary Sketch Plan, WTS, Alternate Scheme. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Preliminary Sketch Plan, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: South Wall of Chapel, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Details of Reredos and Altar for Chapel, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Chapel Altar and Choir, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Reredos for Chapel, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Drawing: Preliminary Detail of Chancel Woodwork, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Blueprint: Front View of Altar End of Chapel, WTS. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Magazine Picture: Seabury Western Seminary Tower. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photo: Seabury Western Seminary Cathedral. (Mapcase-folder ?)
  - Photograph: Entrance to Refectory, Seabury Western Theological Seminary. (same as WTS) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photo of Sketch: Interior of Chapel, Seabury-Western Theological Seminary. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II. Various Midwestern Churches
  - Drawing: Capitol Drive Lutheran Church. (Mapcase-folder ?)
  - Photos of Drawings: First Congregational Church, Kewanee, Illinois (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photo of Drawing: Saint Mark's Church and Parish House, Glen Ellyn, Ill. (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Christmas Card: Trinity Church, Reno, Nevada (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photos of Sketches: Trinity Church, Reno, Nevada., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photo of Sketch: Trinity Church, Reno, Nevada, Lady Chapel and Tower. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Negative photographs and photographs of Sketch: Trinity Church, Reno, Nevada, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - War Post Card: War Shrine, Christ Church Cathedral (Episcopal), Eau Claire, Wisconsin (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photo: Interior of Mortuary Chapel at Eau Claire, Wisconsin (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photo: Front View, Mortuary Chapel at Eau Claire, Wisconsin (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photograph: Glenview, Congregational, Interior. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of exterior: Emmanuel Episcopal Church, La Grange, Ill. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of exterior: Emmanuel Episcopal Church, La Grange, Ill. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlet: Emmanuel Church, La Grange, Ill., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Gives history of church. Tilton chosen, 1924, as architect. Completed 1926. See also #2259.
  - Photos of Drawings: Emmanuel Church, La Grange, Ill. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Drawings: Cross (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Photo of Drawing: Capitol Drive Church, Milwaukee, WTS. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photos of Drawings: Capitol Drive Lutheran Church, Milwaukee, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photo of Sketch: Details of Capitol Drive Lutheran Church, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, April 30, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Two Photos of Sketch: Capitol Drive Lutheran Church, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Leaflet: Lenten Invitation, Capitol Drive Lutheran Church, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photo of Sketch: Capitol Drive Lutheran Church, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photo of Sketch: Capitol Drive Lutheran Church, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Magazine: Capitol Drive Chronicle, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Vol. 22, No. 11-12; Vol. 24, No. 12
  - Blueprint: Interior Capitol Drive Lutheran Church, Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint: Elevated View Capitol Drive Lutheran, Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Negative: St. Christopher's Parish, Oak Park, Ill. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photo of Sketch: St. Mark's Glen Ellyn. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photo of Sketch: Glenview Community Church. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Supplement: "To the Glory of God", Capitol Drive Lutheran Church. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photograph: Altar and Reredos, Emmanuel Episcopal Church. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photo of Sketch: Cathedral Shelter, Chicago. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photo of Sketch: St. Christopher's Parish, Oak Park, Ill. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Magazine Front Page: "The Diocese of Chicago", Preliminary Sketch of Anderson Chapel. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Magazine Article: "The Diocese of Chicago" on completion of seminary buildings. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Negative Photos of Sketch and Pos. Photo: St. Christopher's Parish, Guild Hall and Addition, Oak Park, Ill. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series III. Non-Church Buildings (15 items)
  - Blueprint: Survey of Plot of Land, Evanston. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Blueprint: Survey of Plot of Land, Evanston. (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Photo of Drawing: Highland Park High Gymnasium and Cafeteria. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Drawing: Gymnasium for the School of Education, University of Chicago., 1926 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photo of Sketch: North School, Glencoe, Ill. 1955 (Mapcase-folder ?)
  - Photos of Drawing: North School at Glencoe, Ill., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photograph: Inside of Addition to Diamond T. Motor Car Co. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Christmas Card: Everett Residence, Hinsdale, Ill. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photograph: Everett Residence, Hinsdale, Ill. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photograph: Addition to Diamond T. Motor Car Co., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photo of Sketch: Village Hall and Public Safety Building, Glencoe, Ill. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photo of Sketch: John Archibald Armstrong, Architect, Winter Park, Florida house. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photo of Sketch: Lincolnwood School at Evanston, Illinois, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Blueprints and drawings of Elmira College (Mapcase-folder 2)
- Series IV. Ithaca Area Items
  - Drawing: Diagram of the Gauntlett Memorial Window, St. John's Church at Ithaca, New York, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photos of Sketch: Proposed Congregational Church, Ithaca, New York. Not built, March 5, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Two are 14" x 9" and one is 8" x 5".
- E. Miscellanea - Unidentified, etc.
  - Photo of Sketch: Auditorium. (Mapcase-folder ?)
  - Photo of Sketch: Auditorium, Wilmette. (Mapcase-folder ?)
  - Sketch Print: Triptych in Chapel, St. Paul's Church, New Haven, Conn., American Architect. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Drawing: Detail on Cross, Pauline Hartford Memorial Chapel. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photo of Sketch: Ceiling and Balcony, Aud. O.P & R.F.H.S. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photo of Sketch: Stage from Balcony, Aud. O.P. & R.F.H.S. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photo of Sketch: Aud. of O.P. & R.F.H.S. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photograph: Scaffolding about steeple of Church. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: Two churches (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Drawing: Southwark Cathedral, London Bridge. (Mapcase-folder ?)
  - Drawing: Recreation Center. (Mapcase-folder ?)
  - Drawing: War Memorial or Civic Building. (Box 2, Folder 6)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Paper: Brief History of St. John's Church - Ithaca, N.Y., 1822-1955, A.G. Whitcomb. See Acc. #2308.
Catalogue: "Ecclesiastical Appointments of Distinction." Morhouse-Gorham Co., Chicago, Ill. For Pamphlet Collection.